<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rvest on Data By Dan</title>
    <link>/tags/rvest/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rvest on Data By Dan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/rvest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Personal Transportation Use</title>
      <link>/post/visualizing-personal-transportation-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/visualizing-personal-transportation-use/</guid>
      <description>Summary: I have wanted to dig more into large-scale data visualization for awhile. This small project started out with two goals: web scraping and visualizing movement data. As the project developed, I found that the web scraping took most of the time, and the visualization was best left to well-developed javascript frameworks, rather than developing it from scratch.
Check out the (final visualization)[https://kepler.gl/demo/map?mapUrl=https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/s/vrbbndip8jfvcjr/keplergl_ov2g1b.json].
Webscraping Note: It is extremely important to read and understand the website user agreement for any website from which you might want to scrape data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Personal Use</title>
      <link>/post/personalviz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/personalviz/</guid>
      <description>Note This is an experimental project that has not been fully implemented. The app runs well locally, so I would recommend going over to my GitHub if you are interested in the source code or the final product. That being said, the webscraping element is in violation of the CaBi website user policy, so I do not endorse the use. I am working on developing an alternative form that allows individuals to upload their ridership data after manually exporting from the website.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>