<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Network Analysis on Data By Dan</title>
    <link>https://danbernstein.netlify.com/tags/network-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Network Analysis on Data By Dan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://danbernstein.netlify.com/tags/network-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The John Oliver Effect</title>
      <link>https://danbernstein.netlify.com/post/the-john-oliver-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danbernstein.netlify.com/post/the-john-oliver-effect/</guid>
      <description>Background John Oliver recently discussed genetic editing on Last Week Tonight. Luckily by chance I have had an automated R script running everyday that collects all tweets that mention the term CRISPR, the leading method of genetic editing at this time. Bringing these two events together, I am interested to see how John Oliver discussing genetic editing might impact the level of social media activity surrounding the topic, represented by the tweets captured mentioned CRISPR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Analysis in International Scientific Collaboration</title>
      <link>https://danbernstein.netlify.com/post/crispr-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danbernstein.netlify.com/post/crispr-network/</guid>
      <description>Motivation I have been thinking about networks of science for awhile: collaboration, competition, intellectual property and licensing, etc. At the same time, CRISPR (Clustered Regularly Interspaced Palindromic Repeats) has emerged as the preeminent gene-editing tool in laboratories across the world (sorry TALENs and all you other fun tools). MIT&amp;rsquo;s Broad Institute and UC Berkeley have been in a protracted legal battle over the patent for the technology underlying new advances in medicine, agriculture, and other consumer industries.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>